<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Matt Goodman</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About on Matt Goodman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://goodmattg.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Demand for Cryptocurrency is Demand for Alpha</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/demand-for-crypto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/demand-for-crypto/</guid><description>Demand for Cryptocurrency is Demand for Alpha The Demand: smart people who want lucrative jobs correlated with &amp;ldquo;smartness&amp;rdquo; I still don&amp;rsquo;t get crypto, but I kind of get one of the needs for crypto. If you run in my &amp;ldquo;elite&amp;rdquo; 1 post-grad circle you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that a lot of people talk about finance. Every quantitatively oriented software engineer I meet will introduce themselves and be like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m John. In my free time I like hiking, hanging out with friends, and I do some quantitative trading just for fun.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned using MyPy in Production</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/safe-typing-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/safe-typing-in-python/</guid><description>Lessons Learned using MyPy in Production When we talk about type safety in the context of statically typed languages, we mean that the language builds in a typing checking mechanism into the compiler. No type-check, no compilation.
But in the context of research / algorithms oriented software that has no uptime requirements, the bias coming out of academia is to get the math into code, these days Python, and put it in production.</description></item><item><title>Relational Inductive Biases: a manifesto</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/relation-inductive-biases-a-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/relation-inductive-biases-a-manifesto/</guid><description>Relational Inductive Biases: a manifesto The authors present a succinct and powerful manifesto of the importance of graph networks in artificial intelligence research. The paper is a move to synthesize the previously disjoint field of graph neural networks into a single framework: &amp;ldquo;Graph Networks (GN)&amp;rdquo;.
Thoughts We have a much needed survey paper that unifies graph networks (GNs) and refocuses attention away from the technical details of network composition/functionality back to the marquee goal of building networks that achieve combinatorial generalization through flexible computation on structured representation.</description></item><item><title>Syncing PDFs across Devices in Mendeley</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syncing-pdfs-in-mendeley-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syncing-pdfs-in-mendeley-desktop/</guid><description>Syncing PDFs across Devices in Mendeley Mendeley is a great tool to keep track of papers and citations across multiple devices if you can figure out how to actually enable file (i.e. PDF) syncing across devices. The UX designers were on a lunch break when this one was cooked up. The good news: enabling syncing is easy and you&amp;rsquo;ll never have to think about it again:
Step 1) Open Mendeley Desktop To my knowledge, the sync files across devices setting can only be configured from Mendeley Desktop.</description></item><item><title>Software Sharing in Medical Research</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/software-sharing-in-medical-research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/software-sharing-in-medical-research/</guid><description>Software Sharing in Medical Research I was reading Mohammed AlQuraishi&amp;rsquo;s post1 &amp;ldquo;AlphaFold @ CASP13: What just happened?&amp;rdquo; recently about DeepMind&amp;rsquo;s advance in protein folding. His point about research siloing holding the whole field back resonated with me in light of my current work identifying malignant tumors in ultrasound images. To put it bluntly, it isn&amp;rsquo;t helpful that I can quickly find ten good papers claiming state-of-the-art performance on tumor segmentation if I can&amp;rsquo;t quickly download and verify the model performance on a non-toy dataset.</description></item><item><title>Proving Newton's Binomial Theorem</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/newtons-binomial-theorem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/newtons-binomial-theorem/</guid><description>Proving Newton&amp;rsquo;s Binomial Theorem Prove Newton&amp;rsquo;s Theorem for $t \in \mathbb{R}$ for $|x|&amp;lt;1$. If $t=n$ is any positive integer obtain the standard binomial formula $(a+b)^n=\sum_{k=0}^n\binom{n}{k}a^{n-k}b^k$.
$$(1+x)^t=1+\binom{t}{1}x+\binom{t}{2}x^2+\binom{t}{3}x^3\cdots=\sum_{k=0}^{\infty}\binom{t}{k}x^k$$
My calculus is rusty, so my first and only instinct when I see an infinite series like this with incrementing exponents is to use Taylor&amp;rsquo;s approximation theorem with remainder.
$$f^{n+1}(x) = \underbrace{\sum_{k=0}^{n}f^{(k)}(0)\frac{x^k}{k!}}_\text{T(x)}~+~\underbrace{\frac{1}{n!}\int_0^xt^nf^{n+1}(x-t)~dt}_{R_n(x)}$$
Looking this over, we can tell this is probably a good approach.</description></item><item><title>Theory of Probability (Chapter 1)</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/theory-of-probability-chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/theory-of-probability-chapter-1/</guid><description>Theory of Probability (Chapter 1) Retrospect (03/27/21) I remember this time in my life clearly. It was a mental high point and a physical low point. Unsurprisingly, I only made it through two chapters. Theoretical probability is hard, and I found this material impossible to work through without peer feedback. Life is meant to be lived; I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the pressure to take on masochistic intellectual challenges anymore.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Time Warping for Clustering Time Series Data</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/dynamic-time-warping/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/dynamic-time-warping/</guid><description>Dynamic Time Warping for Clustering Time Series Data Motivation This was for the Wikipedia competition hosted by Kaggle competition to predict future page view counts on Wikipedia. Like so many of the solutions now the winning approach used RNNs to learn a set of hyperparameters on the entire dataset that are then fed in to a predict locally on each time series. This begs comparison to multivel hierarchical models from a Bayesian perspective, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for a later post.</description></item><item><title>Syntactic Tree Kernels</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syntactic-tree-kernels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syntactic-tree-kernels/</guid><description>Syntactic Tree Kernels Motivation This post encapsulates the work I did with Dean Fulgoni for our final project in Big Data Analytics. Credit to Professor Chris Callison-Burch for steering me away from some topics that &amp;ldquo;could easily be Phd theses&amp;rdquo; and to Professor Zachary Ives for being an excellent teacher.
The Problem We Tried to Solve The problem is deviously simple - given two input questions, tell whether the questions ask the same thing (i.</description></item><item><title>Update: Graph-based Model Election Forecasting</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/graph-election-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/graph-election-update/</guid><description>Update: Graph-based Model Election Forecasting While I am no longer directly working on the GSP Election project, I am still an informal advisor to the undergraduates currently working to improve the model. The challenge we currently face is quite intriguing. We have the data: presidential election, senatorial election, median income, demographics, poverty, etc. The new issue is how we combine the graph shift operators from each of these data sets to produce an optimal graph shift operator (that results in minimum norm-1 error).</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/about/</guid><description>About Me Relentless reader and builder. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer with experience in deep-learning based computer vision, distributed AutoML services, platform engineering, and full-stack web development.
In my free time I building things, taking on new challenges, and playing sports. If you have a new challenge, please reach out.
&amp;ndash; Matt
Research and Product Interests Generative content creation and detection for entertainment and defense Blockchain technology to mint &amp;ldquo;authentic&amp;rdquo; - i.</description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/bookshelf/</guid><description>An attempt to track my reading (incomplete) Book Author Started Finished Notes Venture Deals Brad Feld, Jason Mendelson 08/11/21 - The Tsar of Love And Techno Anthony Marra 08/11/21 - Stalingrad Vasily Grossman 08/07/21 - String Theory David Foster Wallace - - Tennis is not an &amp;ldquo;any given Sunday&amp;rdquo; type of sport. There are completely separate planes of competition that never intersect.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/contact/</guid><description> Email: goodmattg &amp;ldquo;[á^t.]&amp;rdquo; protonmail.com replace &amp;ldquo;[á^t.]&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;@&amp;quot; Social Github LinkedIn</description></item><item><title>Quotes</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/quotes/</guid><description>Quotes Excerpt From: Mo Yan &amp;amp; Howard Goldblatt. “Red Sorghum.” Penguin Books, 2012-01-18. Apple Books.
“They killed, they looted, and they defended their country in a valiant, stirring ballet that makes us unfilial descendants who now occupy the land pale by comparison. Surrounded by progress, I feel a nagging sense of our species’ regression”
Excerpt From: Moawad, Trevor. “It Takes What It Takes.” HarperCollins, 2019-11-25. Apple Books.
“You need to be thinking neutrally, making plans, and making good choices so you’re prepared when the pressure arrives.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/resume/</guid><description>Resume available upon request.</description></item></channel></rss>