<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Matt's Log</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Matt's Log</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://goodmattg.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mega-guide to Nvidia CUDA, CUDA Toolkit, CUDA Driver for an Ubuntu 20.04 Nvidia GPU PC Build</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/mega-guide-cuda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/mega-guide-cuda/</guid><description>An Ubuntu 20.04 Nvidia GPU CUDA Guide</description></item><item><title>Thoughts Heading into 2022</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/thoughts-heading-into-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/thoughts-heading-into-2022/</guid><description>Community is everything. Building a network effect through your community is becoming a key marker of success. This much is obvious and written to death in thinkpieces. Tools to actually support that community, to make it more enjoyeable for them to participate are still growing. Think about how Discord went from gaming chat, to the defacto community management platform for web3 / bleeding-edge software projects.
As developers we build these things we think are great&amp;hellip; and then they go nowhere.</description></item><item><title>Deep Learning in 2021</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/how-to-train-a-neural-network-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/how-to-train-a-neural-network-in-2021/</guid><description>Deep Learning in 2021</description></item><item><title>Demand for Cryptocurrency is Demand for Alpha</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/demand-for-crypto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/demand-for-crypto/</guid><description>I don&amp;#39;t get crypto, but I kind of get crypto</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned using MyPy in Production</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/safe-typing-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/safe-typing-in-python/</guid><description>Lessons learned used MyPy in production</description></item><item><title>Relational Inductive Biases: a manifesto</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/relation-inductive-biases-a-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/relation-inductive-biases-a-manifesto/</guid><description>DeepMind, Google Brain, MIT, and University of Edinburgh collaborators produce a manifesto on graph networks</description></item><item><title>Syncing PDFs across Devices in Mendeley</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syncing-pdfs-in-mendeley-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syncing-pdfs-in-mendeley-desktop/</guid><description>Mendeley is a great tool to keep track of papers and citations across multiple devices if you can figure out how to actually enable file (i.e. PDF) syncing across devices. The UX designers were on a lunch break when this one was cooked up.</description></item><item><title>Software Sharing in Medical Research</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/software-sharing-in-medical-research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/software-sharing-in-medical-research/</guid><description>I was reading Mohammed AlQuraishi&amp;#39;s [post][1] &amp;#34;AlphaFold @ CASP13: What just happened?&amp;#34; recently about DeepMind&amp;#39;s advance in protein folding. His point about research siloing holding the whole field back resonated with me in light of my current work identifying malignant tumors in ultrasound images.</description></item><item><title>Proving Newton's Binomial Theorem</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/newtons-binomial-theorem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/newtons-binomial-theorem/</guid><description>An amateur&amp;#39;s attempt at proving Newton&amp;#39;s Binomial Theorem</description></item><item><title>Theory of Probability (Chapter 1)</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/theory-of-probability-chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/theory-of-probability-chapter-1/</guid><description>Retrospect (03/27/21) I remember this time in my life clearly. It was a mental high point and a physical low point. Unsurprisingly, I only made it through two chapters. Theoretical probability is hard, and I found this material impossible to work through without peer feedback. Life is meant to be lived; I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the pressure to take on masochistic intellectual challenges anymore.
A gedanken experiment Do you gain some sort of magic insight if you work through an entire textbook, or is there no light at the end of the tunnel?</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Time Warping for Clustering Time Series Data</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/dynamic-time-warping/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/dynamic-time-warping/</guid><description>This post is as much a meditation on using Dynamic Time Warping (DTW) in production as it is a review of my work. I have so many questions about this subject. If you have any answers, I hope you will reach out.</description></item><item><title>Syntactic Tree Kernels</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syntactic-tree-kernels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/syntactic-tree-kernels/</guid><description>The problem is deviously simple - given two input questions, tell whether the questions ask the same thing (i.e. seek to reveal the same previously unknown knowledge).</description></item><item><title>Update: Graph-based Model Election Forecasting</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/graph-election-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/posts/graph-election-update/</guid><description>While I am no longer directly working on the GSP Election project, I am still an informal advisor to the undergraduates currently working to improve the model. The challenge we currently face is quite intriguing. We have the data: presidential election, senatorial election, median income, demographics, poverty, etc. The new issue is how we combine the graph shift operators from each of these data sets to produce an optimal graph shift operator (that results in minimum norm-1 error).</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/about/</guid><description>About Me Reader and builder. I&amp;rsquo;m an engineer with experience in deep-learning based computer vision, distributed AutoML services, platform engineering, and full-stack web development.
In my free time I like to build things, take on new challenges, and get outside.
&amp;ndash; Matt
Research and Product Interests Infrastructure and tooling to accelerate deep learning Large-scale video understanding &amp;amp; related engineering challenges Generative content creation AutoML for computer vision &amp;amp; deep learning Timeline Year Position Present Sabbatical 2020-2022 Research Engineer in Deep Learning, Computer Vision Group, ByteDance AI Lab.</description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/bookshelf/</guid><description>An attempt to track my reading Book Author Started Finished Notes The Collected Essays, Journalism &amp;amp; Letters George Orwell - 12/17/22 Most of his letter to Parisian Review are uninteresting in the modern context, but the Lion &amp;amp; The Unicorn still feels relevant. It brings consideration of how we approach facism today as a political movement led by real people, not just an abstract historical concept. I&amp;rsquo;m taking a lot from Orwell&amp;rsquo;s ability to accept his own privilege but still thoughtfully consider the headspace of the working class in England.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/contact/</guid><description> Email: goodmattg &amp;ldquo;[á^t.]&amp;rdquo; protonmail.com replace &amp;ldquo;[á^t.]&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; Social Github LinkedIn</description></item><item><title>Quotes</title><link>https://goodmattg.github.io/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://goodmattg.github.io/quotes/</guid><description>Quotes Sun Tzu, The Art of War
“Let your plans be dark and impenetrable as night, and when you move, fall like a thunderbolt.”
Excerpt From: Mo Yan &amp;amp; Howard Goldblatt. “Red Sorghum.” Penguin Books, 2012-01-18. Apple Books.
“They killed, they looted, and they defended their country in a valiant, stirring ballet that makes us unfilial descendants who now occupy the land pale by comparison. Surrounded by progress, I feel a nagging sense of our species’ regression”</description></item></channel></rss>